Contact

Eshanya Samruddhi, Ashwath Nagar, HBR Layout, Bengaluru, Karnataka 560043 7530000458 (Mobile) saiteja7yalamarthi@gmail.co m

www.linkedin.com/in/sai-tejayalamarthi-a2141a18a (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

PySpark

Amazon Web Services (AWS) Snowflake

Sai Teja Yalamarthi

AWS Python Developer | Delta GTH Bangalore | Delta Airlines Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Summary

Greetings!

I am a passionate and experienced AWS Python Developer and Data Engineer with a strong drive for success and a rapid learning capability, I am highly motivated and dedicated to achieving outstanding results in every endeavor I undertake.

I Specialize in:

- ->Data Pipeline Design and Deployment with a strong background in designing and deploying data pipelines on AWS cloud infrastructure using AWS CDK and Python
- ->Experienced programmer with Excellent analytical skills with a proven track record of developing accelerators and automation python scripts which reduced considerable amount of development time and effort.
- ->Strong SQL and ETL skills, Over the years, I have gained extensive experience in ingesting data from various sources into different SQL platforms involving complex queries/mappings.

I possess an enthusiastic attitude towards embracing new technologies and eagerly taking on challenges to further enhance my skills and contribute to impactful projects.

Experience

Delta Air Lines AWS Python Developer July 2022 - Present (2 years 9 months) Bengaluru, Karnataka, India My work is primarily based on designing and deploying data pipelines for aws cloud infrastructure using aws-cdk in python to ingest data from different sources.

- o I have built ingestion pipelines in AWS Glue using Pyspark to migrate the complex Informatica workflows involving 400+table to target database.

 o I have worked on designing MWAA(Apache Airflow) based solution for the ETL process where i have designed the private airflow environment in AWS using CDK and have done POC on the usage of airflow for ETL process.

 o Currently working on converting multiple informatica workflows to AWS Cloud and orchestrating them using MWAA.
- o I have developed a generic step function where the job metadata and run details are stored on DynamoDB and based on the job step, workflow is generated and an map iterator iterates through all the tasks and create datasets on s3 using Athena queries or load to database using AWS Lambdas based on the job metadata. it includes retry of a failed step on its own or manual retrying the failed step alone or retrying the whole workflow.
- o I have worked on ingesting streaming data from kafka using lambdas. o I have done a POC to implement a solution to store s3 data in apache-
- iceberg tables to perform ACID transactions using Amazon Athena on top of S3.
- o I have done a POC to develop a glue job to perform etl on iceberg s3 data.
- o I have done performance testing on glue to ingest large s3 files to teradata.

Wipro Limited
Data Engineer

September 2020 - July 2022 (1 year 11 months)

Bangalore Urban, Karnataka, India

Developed many SQL interfaces, python accelerators, and received client appreciation on number of occasions for my efforts and delivery.

Extensively worked on python scripting, SQL development(Snowflake, Hive, Oracle, Postgres, Redshift), AWS(s3,redshift,cloudwatch,stepfunctions).

Client: Freedom Mortgage:

o I have created a python flask api to map columns of target tables to the snowflake shared source tables based on information schema which reduced 70% of efforts needed to complete the task.

o I have developed a python script to do the fuzzymap of customer data and 3rd party data using rapidfuzz.

o I have done exploratory data analysis to find trends on big data sets using vaex.

o I have created a python accelerator to do the load testing from snowflake shared source table to snowflake target where the load is happened via stored procedure.

o I have created a python api which takes zipcode as input and returns the addresses with geo coordinates present in that zipcode in a json.

Client: Union Bank (MUFG):

o I worked on the framework automation python scripts(autosys) to execute job and update the job details into the postgresdb.

o I created a python accelerator to parallelly create views in RedShift based on the metadata of the tables stored in postgresdb, which reduced considerable amount of man hours needed to complete the task.

o I collaborated with syncsort team to create a python script which reads the syncsort log file and creates the control files out of it.

Education

VIT_Vellore Institute of Technology

Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Electronics and Communications

Engineering · (2016 - 2020)